Amiri Baraka papers 6909686
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series II: Writings, 1958-2009
  - Subseries 3: Plays and Performances, 1966-2009
    - Performance Notes (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Portrait of the Lion, 1998
      - Drafts, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Performance Notes, undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Printed Material, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Score, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Primitive World, 1983-1997
      - Budget, undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - Contract, 1983-1984 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Drafts, undated
        - Proofs, undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
        - Typescript, undated (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - Press Release, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Printed Material, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - The Prophet, undated (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Itineraries, 1988-2009 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Real Song, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - A Recent Killing, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Red, Black, and Green, (1970s) (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Remembering We Selves, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Ritual Massacre, undated (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Round About Midnight, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - S-1, 1976; (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 32-33)
    - A Skit For Young Boys, undated (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - The Sidnee Poet Heroical, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - The Sisyphus Syndrome, 1992-2004; (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 36-37)
    - Slaughter in Harlem, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - The Slave--French Translation by Pierre Saintons, undated (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Slave Ship--Drafts and Printed Material, 1966-1980 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Song, 1980-1983
      - Budget, Contract, Correspondence, and Press Release, 1980-1983 (Box 27, Folder 41)
      - Drafts, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 42)
      - Photos, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 43)
      - Printed Material, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - The Toilet--Japanese Production, undated (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Vomit and the Jungle Bunnies, undated (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Waiting for Death to Die, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - "We Said No", undated (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - What was the Relationship of the Lone Ranger to the Means of Production?--Correspondence, Notes, Photos, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Workers of the World Unite, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4: Screenplays, 1983-1996
    This series is comprised of the manuscripts, correspondence, and press material of screenplays written by Baraka or with which he was associated as a co-writer, actor, or interviewee, including W.E.B. DuBois: A Biography in Four Voices, The Life Sign, and Miles!. The materials are arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Bulworth, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - In Motion: Amiri Baraka--Press Release, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - The Life Sign, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Miles!, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - WEB DuBois Film Project, 1985-1992; (2 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 8-9)
  - Subseries 5: Fiction, 1973-2003
    This series contains holograph and typescript drafts, as well as proofs and galleys, of Baraka's published and unpublished fiction. Along with drafts of many individual short stories, there are also contained herein full drafts of story collections and novels 6 Persons, The Fiction of LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka, The New World, and Tales of the Out and Gone. The material in this series is arranged alphabetically by title.
    - General, (1999) (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - 6 Persons--Typescript, 1973-1974; (3 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 11-13)
    - "999 With String", undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - "The Election Machine Warehouse", undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - The Fiction of LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka, 2000; (2 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 16-17)
    - "The Great Music Robbery", undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - "Honky's Return", undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - "Honky Tonk Bud", undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - "A Letter", undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - "Negroduction", undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - The New World, undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - "Politics at the End of the 20th Century,", undated (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - "Post and Pre Mortem Dialog", 2003 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - "Ray Robinson,", undated (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - "Some Missing Bulworth Scrolls", undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Tales of the Out and Gone--Introduction, undated (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - "You", undated (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Subseries 6: Editorship, 1958-2007
    Baraka's work as an editor of various literary, arts, and political journals and little magazines is the focus of this series. Included are the typescripts and galleys of individual issues, correspondence and internal editorial matter, drafts of individual submissions and published items, artwork, and published material for Yugen, Cricket, The Black Nation, Rising Tide, and, most comprehensively, the political newsletter and newspaper Unity & Struggle. The material is arranged alphabetically by journal or magazine title.
    - The Black Nation, 1981-1986
      - "Introduction to Black Nation 2", 1982 (Box 28, Folder 30)
      - Issue 3 Typescript, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - Issue Galleys, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 32)
      - "Issue on Music" Typescript, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 33)
      - Submissions, 1983-1986 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Cricket--Submissions, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Rising Tide No. 1, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Unity & Struggle, 1975-2007
      - Correspondence, 1975-2006; (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 16-17)
      - Article Drafts, 1989-2007
        - By Baraka, 1989-2007; (5 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 18-22)
        - By Others, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - Organizational Material, 1989-1998; (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 24-25)
      - Unity & Struggle Issues, 1977-2005; (13 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1-13)
      - Unity & Struggle Issues, 1981-1987 (Box 89)
    - Yugen, 1958-2002
      - Drawings, (2002) (Box 28, Folder 37)
      - Issues 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 8, 1958-1962 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Subseries 7: New Jersey Poet Laureate and Somebody Blew Up America Materials, 2001-2004
    This subseries contains the manuscript drafts of Baraka's poem "Somebody Blew Up America," as well as contracts, orders, and other materials relating to the print edition. Also found here are materials surrounding the controversial afterlife of the poem in which Baraka was removed from the position of New Jersey Poet Laureate—materials include drafts of essays about his removal, correspondence, letters of support and petitions, press packets, and schedules of NJPL events prior to Baraka's dismissal.
    - General, 2002-2004 (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, 2002-2004; (4 Folders) (Box 67)
    - Confirmation Letter, 2002 (Box 67)
    - Letters of Support and Petitions, 2002 (Box 67)
    - Press Packet, 2002 (Box 67)
    - Printed Material, 2002-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 67)
    - Schedules and Budgets, 2002-2004; (2 Folders) (Box 67)
    - Writings, 2001-2004
      - General, 2002-2003 (Box 67)
      - By Others, 2002 (Box 67)
      - "I Will Not Apologize, I Will Not Resign", 2002 (Box 67)
      - "Critical Questions of the Anti-Defamation League", undated (Box 67)
      - "New Jersey's Poet Laureate Fights Back", 2002 (Box 67)
      - "Nincompoops of the New Jersey Legislature: You Can't Fire Poetry!", 2002 (Box 67)
      - "Somebody Blew Up America,", 2001-2004
        - General, 2002-2004 (Box 67)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 67)
        - Somebody Blew Up America and Other Poems, 2003
          - Orders, 2003 (Box 67)
          - Introduction, 2003 (Box 67)
          - Contract, 2003 (Box 67)
        - Broadsides and Posters, undated (Box 67)
        - Chapbook, 2001 (Box 67)
  - Subseries 8: Writings By Others, 1966-2008
    Arranged by form, and within these sub-groupings, alphabetically by author, the series contains manuscript drafts, and some correspondence, of fiction, non-fiction, plays, screenplays, anthologies, and poetry written by others and held by Baraka. The bulk of these writings are unmarked. Highlights include writings by Stanley Crouch, Larry Neal, Quincy Troupe, Komozi Woodard, Thomas Sayers Ellis, Sam Greenlee, Robert Stone, Ben Caldwell, Ossie Davis, Toni Morrison, Diane DiPrima, David Henderson, Clarence Major, Marvin X, AB Spellman, Manning Marable, Spike Lee, and Aldon Nielsen.
    - Poetry, 1966-2008
      - General, 1970-2007 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - General, 1970-2007; (3 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
      - Alphabetical by Author, 1967-2008
        - A, 1981-2007; (4 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 2-5)
        - B, 1986-2003; (3 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 6-8)
        - C, 1978-1999 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - D, 1985-2004; (3 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 10-12)
        - E, 1980-2003 (Box 30, Folder 13)
        - F, 1989-2004 (Box 30, Folder 14)
        - G, 1986-2003 (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - H, 1970-2006; (3 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 2-4)
        - I, (2004) (Box 31, Folder 5)
        - J, 1977-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
        - K, 1987-2002 (Box 31, Folder 8)
        - L, 1967-2003 (Box 31, Folder 9)
        - M, 1980-2005; (3 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 10-12)
        - N, 1985-2007; (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
        - O, 1977-2005; (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 15-16)
        - P, 1981-2004; (2 Folders) (Box 89)
        - Q, undated (Box 89)
        - R, 1981-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 89)
        - S, 1982-2008; (3 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 4-6)
        - T, 1976-1999; (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
        - V, (2000s) (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - W, 1970-2005; (3 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 10-12)
        - Y, (2005) (Box 32, Folder 13)
        - Z, undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Al-Jahizz, Ibrahim (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - Abrams, Sam (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Baraka, Ahi, undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Baraka, Amina (Sylvia Jones), (2003) (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - Baraka, Kimako, 1972-1984 (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - Baraka, Ras, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - Beatty, Paul, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Beehive: A Collection of Contemporary Writing, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Brisby, Stewart, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Cantalupo, Charles, 1970-1981; (3 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 4-6)
      - Cardenal, Ernesto--Cosmic Canticle, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
      - Cave Canem, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Cleage, Pearl, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Coke, Allison, A.H., undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Conway, Arthur Lee, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Cortez, Jayne, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Craft, Howard, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Creeley, Robert Signed Broadside, 1995 (Box 49)
      - Crenshaw, Thomas, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Crouch, Stanley, 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Davis, Randall, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Dawson, Fielding, 1994-1998 (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - DiPrima, Diane, 2001-2006 (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - Fast Talk, Full Volume, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - For My People, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Fridge, Lanell, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - Gayton, Tomas, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - Glanville, Cecil, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 24)
      - Gilbert, Derrick, undated (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - Gray-El, Ty--Breath of My Ancestors, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Henderson, David, undated (Box 33, Folder 26)
      - Hoagland, Everett, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 27)
      - Inclined to Speak, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 28)
      - Iman, Yuseff, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 29)
      - Ismaili, Rashidah, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Katz, Eliott, 1987-1990 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - King, Basil, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Klein, Jim, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Liebler, ML, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Major, Clarence, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Marvin X, 2005 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Mason Dixon Line, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Medina, Tony, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - National Crime Victims Rights Week Anti-Violence Poetry Contest Submissions, 2005 (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Nielsen, A.L., 1982 (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Nowak, Mark, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - Odamtten, Vincent O., 1989-1990 (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - Parker, William, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 14)
      - Pennsylvania Council of the Arts Submissions, undated; (6 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 15-20)
      - Pennsylvania Council of the Arts Submissions, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
      - Pfistez, Arthur, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Raber, Erin, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Rivera, Louis, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Sanchez, Sonia, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Sekou, Lasana, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Sinclair, John, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Spellman, AB, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Tielken, Jantje, 2006 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Tillman, George, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Untitled Anthology, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 12-14)
      - Untitled MS, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 15-17)
      - Valadez, Luis, 2006 (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - Washairi Umoja--Prison Poem Anthology, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Wright, Jeff, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 20)
      - Yoes, Ronald, undated (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Non-Fiction, 1969-2008
      - General, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 22-23)
      - Alphabetical By Author, 1974-2008
        - A, 1988-2005; (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
        - B, 1974-2000 (Box 36, Folder 3)
        - C, 1987-2002 (Box 36, Folder 4)
        - D, 1987-2006 (Box 36, Folder 5)
        - E, 1987-2002 (Box 36, Folder 6)
        - F, 1995-2003 (Box 36, Folder 7)
        - G, 1992-2000 (Box 36, Folder 8)
        - H, 1977-2000 (Box 36, Folder 9)
        - I, 2003 (Box 36, Folder 10)
        - J, 1987-2000 (Box 36, Folder 11)
        - K, 1987-1997 (Box 36, Folder 12)
        - L, 1983-1999; (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 13-14)
        - M, 1997-2008 (Box 37, Folder 1)
        - N, 1997-2000 (Box 37, Folder 2)
        - O, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 3)
        - P, 1997-2007; (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 4-5)
        - R, 1978-2002 (Box 37, Folder 6)
        - S, 1980-1998; (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
        - T, 1984-1985 (Box 37, Folder 9)
        - U, undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
        - V, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 11)
        - W, 1989-2001 (Box 37, Folder 12)
        - Y, undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
        - Z, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - Abdulla, Ahmed, undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - Aranowitz, Al, 1989-1995 (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - Anderson, Sheila, 2002 (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 2000; (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
      - Ahmad, Muhammad, undated (Box 28, Folder 39)
      - Arnold, James LaVar, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Alkalimat, Abdul, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Austerlitz, Paul, 2002 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - About Baraka, 1981-2006 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Baldwin Manuscript, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Baraka, Amiri Jr., undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Bios (Others), undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Blackburn, Regina Naasisah, 2002 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Boyd, Herb, 2004 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Brown, Claude, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Campbell, Douglass, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Cash, Malcolm, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Chalto, Doctor E. Pelikan, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Chude-Sokei, Louis, undated (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - Clark, Sharon Minor,1985 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Conversations: An Evening with Nate Mackey and Kamau Brathwaite, 1997; (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 17-18)
      - Collins, Patricia Hill, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 19-20)
      - Coke, Allison A.H., undated; (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 21-22)
      - Copland, Anthony, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 23)
      - Daniels, Douglas, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 24)
      - Davis, Angela Y.--Incarcerated Women, undated (Box 38, Folder 25)
      - Dawson, Michael--Why Vote?, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 26)
      - Edwards, Harry, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Flowers, Arthur, 2001; (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 2-3)
      - Franklin, VP, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Gaffney, Floyd, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Gaines, Kevin, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Gems, Gerald, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Goldman, Anita, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Graham, Joseph, 1980; (4 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 9-12)
      - Harding, Vincent, 1990; (4 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 13-16)
      - Hare, Bruce, 2002 (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - Halsey, William, undated (Box 39, Folder 18)
      - Harris, William J., undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - Hay, Sam, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - Henderson, David, 1984; (4 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 21-24)
      - Henderson, Shaun, 2003 (Box 39, Folder 25)
      - Hungerford, David, undated (Box 40)
      - Jones, Coyt, undated (Box 40)
      - Jones, Mack, 1984-1988 (Box 40)
      - Kennedy, Adrienne, 1990 (Box 40)
      - Lee, Spike, 1990 (Box 40)
      - Marable, Manning, 1987-1991; (3 Folders) (Box 40)
      - Marvin X, 1994-2003; (4 Folders) (Box 40)
      - Morse, James, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Montclair, Medley, 1991 (Box 40)
      - McKissack, Patricia, 1997 (Box 40)
      - Melham, D.H., 1977 (Box 40)
      - McWorter, Gerald, 1984 (Box 40)
      - McAdoo, Bill, undated (Box 40)
      - Mangione, Jerry, 1980 (Box 40)
      - Madden, Corinne, 1997 (Box 40)
      - Nelson, William, undated (Box 40)
      - Nelson, Angela, 1996; (3 Folders) (Box 40)
      - Neal, Larry, 1988; (2 Folders) (Box 41)
      - New Jersey State Council on the Arts Applications, 1985; (9 Folders) (Box 146)
      - Natamba, Kofi, 2007 (Box 41)
      - Olaniyan, Tejumola, 1993 (Box 41)
      - Parenti, Michael, 2005 (Box 41)
      - Press Releases, 1981-2000 (Box 41)
      - Proud Flesh, 2002 (Box 41)
      - Ryan, Paul, 1979 (Box 41)
      - Rifkin, Jeremy, 1980 (Box 41)
      - Rahman, Aishah, 1999 (Box 41)
      - Saiyah, 1982; (2 Folders) (Box 41)
      - Salaam, Kalamu ya, 1996 (Box 41)
      - Sandoval, Jose-Luis (Box 41)
      - Stanford, Max, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 41)
      - Stevenson, Bonita, undated (Box 41)
      - Spencer, Norman, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 41)
      - San Juan, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 42)
      - Smith, Randy Lane, 1984 (Box 42)
      - Sales, William, 1994 (Box 42)
      - Saleem, Habibullah, undated (Box 42)
      - Sautter, Carola, 1993; (2 Folders) (Box 42)
      - Toure, Sekou, undated (Box 42)
      - "Trade Unionist Politics and Social-Democratic Politics", undated (Box 42)
      - Tyson, Tim, undated (Box 42)
      - Tobin, Eugene, undated (Box 42)
      - Taylor, Clyde, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 42)
      - Quincy Troupe Bibliography, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Untitled Manuscripts, undated; (6 Folders) (Box 42)
      - Vincent, Ted, 1989-1991; (3 Folders) (Box 43)
      - Walker, Wyatt Tee, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Washington, Jerome, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Wong, G.T., undated (Box 43)
      - Woodard, Komozi, 1995 (Box 43)
    - Fiction, 1982-2003 (Box 44)
      - General, 1982-2003; (4 Folders) (Box 44)
      - Ashanti, James, 1986 (Box 44)
      - Bambara, Toni Cade, undated (Box 44)
      - Bird Lives, undated (Box 44)
      - Cruz, Ricardo, 1994 (Box 44)
      - Doneshvar, Siemin, 1984 (Box 44)
      - Double or Nothing and All That Jazz, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 44)
      - Eason, Keenan, 1994; (2 Folders) (Box 44)
      - Ellison, Marvin, 1995; (2 Folders) (Box 44)
      - Ellis, Thomas Sayers, undated (Box 44)
      - Evans, Mari, undated (Box 44)
      - Falaq, Fatima Dana (Box 44)
      - Flowers, Arthur, 1985; (2 Folders) (Box 45)
      - Greenlee, Sam, undated (Box 45)
      - Greer, Brian (Box 45)
      - Hendricks, Obery, (2 Folders) (Box 45)
      - Kennedy, Adrienne, 1990 (Box 45)
      - Knight, Michael Muhammad, undated (Box 45)
      - Langston, George, 1991 (Box 45)
      - Lewis, Stephanie, 1983 (Box 45)
      - Pfister, Arthur, 1988 (Box 45)
      - Simanga, Michael, 1998 (Box 45)
      - Stone, Robert, undated (Box 45)
      - Surgal, Jon, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 45)
      - Wonger, B, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 45)
      - Young, Darlene, undated (Box 45)
    - Music and Song Lyrics, 1984-1999 (Box 45)
    - Plays, 1968-2004 (Box 46)
      - General, 1981-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 46)
      - Ain't Never Been Told, 1992 (Box 46)
      - Akinde, Akindele, 1992 (Box 46)
      - All For One, undated (Box 46)
      - Allison, Hughes, undated (Box 46)
      - Berry, Steven, 1986 (Box 46)
      - Barns, Larry Jr., 1973 (Box 46)
      - Berlin, Jimmy, undated (Box 46)
      - Bones, 1996 (Box 46)
      - Briley, John, 1985 (Box 46)
      - Broadnax, Steve, 2004 (Box 46)
      - Brown, Theodore, 1938 (Box 46)
      - Brownell, John C., undated (Box 46)
      - Bush, Carol, 1997 (Box 46)
      - Caldwell, Ben, undated (Box 46)
      - Courtney, Ward, undated (Box 46)
      - Croom, Phyllis, 2005 (Box 46)
      - Dalili, Davis, 1983 (Box 46)
      - Davis, Ossie, 1990 (Box 46)
      - Degelman, Charles, 1985 (Box 46)
      - Farah, Nuruddin, undated (Box 46)
      - Garen, Leo and Jack Baran, 1991 (Box 46)
      - Greaves, Willaim, 1987 (Box 46)
      - Hall, Katori, undated (Box 46)
      - Harris, Bill, 1991 (Box 47)
      - Holt, L., 1968 (Box 47)
      - Howard, Kim, undated (Box 47)
      - Johnson, Hall, undated (Box 47)
      - Jones, Clarence, 1989 (Box 47)
      - Jones, Maria, 1993 (Box 47)
      - Kallas, John, 1981-1986 (Box 47)
      - King, Michael, undated (Box 47)
      - Kirk, Thomas, undated (Box 47)
      - Leonard, Chico, 2001 (Box 47)
      - Lima, Frank, 1989 (Box 47)
      - Mahan, Steven Samuel, 1987 (Box 47)
      - Malone, Leonard, 1978 (Box 47)
      - Marvin X, 1995 (Box 47)
      - Mda, Zakes, undated (Box 47)
      - Milner, Ron, 1978 (Box 47)
      - Moncur, Grachan, undated (Box 47)
      - Moore, Dorthey, undated (Box 47)
      - Moran, Brian, undated (Box 47)
      - Morrison, Toni, 1985 (Box 47)
      - Msema-Kweli, Kwane, undated (Box 47)
      - Nassor, Anthony, undated (Box 47)
      - Nell, Scott, undated (Box 47)
      - Panama, Fred, 1982 (Box 47)
      - Penny, Rob, 1986 (Box 47)
      - Sciler, Conrad, undated (Box 47)
      - Silvera, John, undated (Box 47)
      - Smith, Deron, 1981 (Box 47)
      - Smith, J.A., undated (Box 47)
      - Tombrello, Tom, undated (Box 47)
      - Tyler, Kenneth--The Nam Gig, 1988 (Box 47)
      - Tyler, Kenneth--The Nam Gig, 1988; (3 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 4-6)
      - Wadud, Ali, 1980 (Box 47)
      - Wallace, Rudy, undated (Box 47)
      - Ward, Jay, 2002 (Box 47)
      - Ward, Theodore, undated (Box 43)
      - Washington, Jerome, undated (Box 43)
      - Wells, Frank, undated (Box 43)
      - Wellman, John, 1982 (Box 43)
      - Wesley, Richard, undated (Box 43)
      - White, Joseph, undated (Box 43)
      - Wisdom, Anthony, undated (Box 43)
    - Anthologies and Journals, 1989-2003
      - Baraka, Ras--The Dark Room Anthology, 1989; (3 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 7-9)
      - Collins, Evelyn, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - In Your Face, undated (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Roll Call, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 12-14)
- Series III: Teaching, 1976-2006